Charles Mingus Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Iconography (Box 67, Box 81, Box-folder 83/4-7)
  - Awards and Award Nominations
    - University of California, Berkeley: Hall of Fame Award, 1978 (Box-folder 81/3)
    - District of Columbia, Washington, D.C.: Declaration of Charles Mingus Day, Oct. 22, 1979 (Box-folder 81/4)
    - ASCAP: ASCAP-Deems Taylor Award, 1990 (Box-folder 81/5)
  - Artwork
    - Painting titled "Space Soul", by Elliott Cola (Box-folder 83/4)
    - Record album cover art (Box-folder 83/5-6)
    - Miscellaneous [drawings] (Box-folder 83/7)
  - Picture Postcards [blank] (Box-folder 67/21)
    - Eight Portrait postcards of famous jazz musicians
    - Japanese Cuisine
    - Lake Lungern, Switzerland
    - Pennsylvania: scenes from the state
    - Santa Fe, New Mexico
    - Frank Sinatra
    - South America
- Printed Matter (Box 75-76, Box 80, Box 82, Box-folder 53/3-4)
  The Printed Matter series consists of his personal collection of articles, magazines, newsletters, and press releases, etc. relating to himself as composer and mucisian.
  Printed Matter series is arranged as follows:
  Articles & clippings, arranged chronologically by date.
  Books and pamphlets, arranged alphabetically by title.
  Organiztions and affiliations, arranged alphabetically by organization name.
  Programs:
  With and without Mingus, arranged chronologically by date.
  Special tributes, arranged alphabetically by name or subject.
  Promotional material, arranged alphabetically by format type (brochures, discographies, flyers, etc.) then chronologically by date.
  Miscellaneous publications, arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Articles & Clippings [miscellaneous], 1957-1975 (Box-folder 53/3, Box-folder 75/1)
    - 1957-1975 [includes undated] (Box-folder 75/1)
    - Oversized (Box-folder 53/3)
  - Books and Pamphlets (Box-folder 75/2-10)
    - Building upon Raga'Shree, [by] Antonio Claudio Carvalho. London: The Man Ray Dog Rocket Society, 1972 (Box-folder 75/2)
    - Dancing, poems by Al Young. New York: Corinth Books, 1969 (Box-folder 75/3)
    - The Empire finals at Verona, poems by Jonathan Williams. Highlands, N. Carolina: Jargon 30, 1959 (Box-folder 75/4)
    - The ghetto sparkles, by Jeanne Paris. New York: The Long Island Sunday Press, 1972 (Box-folder 75/5)
    - The greatest thing in the world, [by] Henry Drummond. Mount Vernon, NY: Peter Pauper Press, [ca. 1964] (Box-folder 75/6)
    - Guide to good dining. New York: The New York Times, 1962. (Box-folder 75/7)
    - Hommage a Billie Holiday, [by] Walter Coleman. Paris: Karin Moutet, 1961 (Box-folder 75/8)
    - O' Harlem, [by] Jack Micheline. N.l.: Jack Micheline, 1961 (Box-folder 75/9)
    - The people of the all, by Lonnie Foy and Shirley Powers. N.l.: Shirley Powers, 1973 (Box-folder 75/10)
  - Organizations and Affiliations (Box 75/11-19)
    - British Actors' Equity Association: the Thirtieth Annual Report of the Council (1960-61) (Box-folder 75/11)
    - Broadcast Music, Inc.: News About Music & Writers, Feb. 1962 (Box-folder 75/12)
    - The Duke Ellington Society (Box-folder 75/13)
    - Fellowship of Reconciliation (Box-folder 75/14)
    - The Ford Foundation (Box-folder 75/15)
    - International Platform Association (Box-folder 75/16)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Box-folder 75/17)
      - Brochures
      - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous
    - The Strata Corporation (Box-folder 75/18)
    - Timothy Leary Defense Fund (Box-folder 75/19)
  - Programs [concerts, festivals, lectures, workshops] (Box-folder 75/20-23, Box-folder 76/1-4)
    - With Mingus
      - 1957, Nov. 15: The Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art presents "Music in the Making" (Box-folder 75/20)
      - 1962, July 6-8: Newport Jazz Festival, Newport '62
      - 1964, July-Aug.: Jazz at the Fair Jazz Festival
      - 1970, Nov. 5: Berliner Jazz Tage (Berlin Jazz Days) (Box-folder 75/21)
      - 1971, Oct.: City Center Joffrey Ballet
      - 1971: Newport Jazz Festival 1971
      - 1972, Luglio (July) 28-30: 4 Festival Internazionale del Jazz (Box-folder 75/22)
      - 1973, Nov. 23: Welcome to an Evening with Charles Mingus
      - 1974, 17-18 Agosto (Aug.): Teatro Municipal do Rio de Janeiro (3 copies)
      - 1975, 17-19 Juli: Jazz Festivalen Ahus
      - 1975, Nov.: X Festival Internacional de Jazz de Barcelona (2 copies)
      - 1975: Beogradski Jazz Festival (2 copies)
      - 1976, April 9-18: New Orleans 1976 Jazz & Heritage Festival (Box-folder 75/23)
      - 1977, 2 de junio: Teatro Coliseo, Amigos de la Musica
      - 1977, 3 de junio: Ciclo Musical 1977
      - 1977, June 24-July 4: Newport Jazz Festival New York [schedule]
      - 1977, 12-17 July: 11th Montreux International Festival
      - 1978, April 29: The Great Hall, Cooper Union
    - Without Mingus
      - 1957-71 (Box-folder 76/1)
      - 1972-79 (Box-folder 76/2)
    - Special Tributes (Box-folder 76/3)
      - Ornette Coleman
      - John Coltrane
      - Duke Ellington
      - Max Gordon
      - Dick Gregory
      - Frank O'Hara
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 76/4)
  - Promotional Material (Box-folder 53/4, Box-folder 76/5-16)
    - Brochures (Box-folder 76/5)
    - Discographies (Box-folder 76/6)
    - Flyers (Box-folder 76/7)
    - Oversized flyers & posters (Box-folder 53/4)
    - Posters (Box-folder 76/8)
      - Publicity
      - Ted Curson (Box-folder 76/9)
      - Eric Dolphy (Box-folder 76/10)
      - Charlie Haden (Box-folder 76/11)
      - Jimmy Knepper (Box-folder 76/12)
      - Don Pullen (Box-folder 76/13)
      - Artie Shaw (Box-folder 76/14)
      - Tap Happening (Box-folder 76/15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 76/16)
  - Miscellaneous Publications (Box-folder 53/3, Box-folder 76/17-18, Box 80, Box 82)
    - Bulletins and Press Releases (Box-folder 76/17)
    - Magazines and Newspapers
      - Black Sports: Jan. 1976 (Box 80)
      - Changes in the Arts: March 1980 (3 copies) (Box 80)
      - Continental Film Review: July 1961 (Box 80)
      - Daily News: April 8, 1968 [Martin Luther King, Jr. assassination] (Box 82)
      - Down Beat: Nov. 14, Nov. 28, 1957; Feb. 20, March 6, 1958; June 23, Sept. 1, 1960; March 28, 1963; Aug. 27, 1964; June 2, 1966 (Box 80)
      - Ebony: March 1978 (Box 82)
      - Esquire: Nov. 1960; Jan. 1964 (Box 82)
      - Hi Fi/Stereo Review: May 1961 (Box 82)
      - International Musician: Nov. 1960; March 1966 (Box 82)
      - Jazz: July-Aug. 1963 (Box 80)
      - Jazz Monthly: Sept., Dec. 1957; July 1958 (Box 80)
      - The Jazz Review: June 1960 (Box 80)
      - Jet: Sept. 6, 1962 (Box 80)
      - Look: March 1978 (Box 82)
      - Metronome: June 1960; Aug. 1961 (Box 80)
      - Muhammad Speaks: Aug. 2, 1963 (Box 82)
      - Music Vendor: June 2, 1958 (Box 80)
      - New York Times: Aug. 9, 1982 [President Nixon resignation] (Box-folder 53/3)
      - New York Times Magazine: July 1, 1980 (Box 82)
      - Orkester Journalen: Mars, April 1966 (Box 80)
      - Show: Feb. 1964 (Box 82)
      - Tan: Jan. 1962 (Box 82)
      - Vogue: Nov. 15, 1965 (Box 82)
    - Monograph Publications (Box-folder 76/18)
      - The Benvenuto: Oct.-Nov. 1960
      - Discovery: [1975?]
      - Panarama: Feb. 1968 (2 copies)
      - Three Mothers: Their Life Stories: 1968
- Personal (Box 68-74, Box 84)
  The Personal series consists of Mingus' private archives and an unusual collection of physical effects associated with him.
  Personal Papers series is arranged alphabetically by subject or name (i.e.correspondence, financial papres, legal file, etc.) then chronologically by date.
  - Correspondence (Box-folder 68/1)
    - Family
    - Grreeting cards
    - Personal notes
    - Other
  - Financial Papers
    - Assets of Charles Mingus and Sue (Ungaro) Mingus
      - Financial breakdown (Box-folder 68/2)
      - Real estate (Box-folder 68/3)
        - Applications
        - Contracts
        - Correspondence
        - Miscellaneous notes
        - Miscellany
    - Banking
      - Bank of America [checking account] (Box-folder 68/4)
        - Cancelled checks ... see Box 79
        - Miscellaneous
      - Bankers Trust Company [checking account] (Box-folder 68/5)
        - Cancelled checks ... see Box 79
        - Miscellaneous
      - Chase Manhattan Bank (Chase National Bank) [savings and checking accounts] (Box-folder 68/6)
        - Cancelled checks ... see Box 79
        - Correspondence
        - Records of deposits
        - Statements
        - Miscellaneous
      - Chemical Corn Exchange Bank [checking account] (Box-folder 68/7)
        - Cancelled checks ... see Box 79
        - Miscellaneous
      - Edison Savings and Loan Association [savings account] (Box-folder 68/8)
        - Miscellaneous
      - First National City Bank [safe deposit box] (Box-folder 68/9)
        - Miscellaneous
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 68/10)
    - Bills & Creditors
      - Utilities (Box-folder 68/11)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 68/12)
    - Household Manintenance
      - Automobiles (Box-folder 68/13)
        - Contracts
        - Correspondence
        - Insurance policies
        - Maintenance
        - Miscellaneous
      - Receipts
        - Amusements (Box-folder 68/14)
        - Child care (Box-folder 68/15)
        - Clothing (Box-folder 68/16)
          - Dry cleaning
          - Purchases
        - Credit card: American Express (Box-folder 68/17)
        - Food and beverages (Box-folder 68/18)
        - Home repair and home furnishings (Box-folder 68/19)
        - Mailing/shipping (Box-folder 68/20)
      - Utilities
        - Electric (Box-folder 69/1)
        - Telephone (Box-folder 69/2)
        - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 69/3)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 69/4)
    - Taxes
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 69/5)
      - Income tax returns (Box-folder 69/6)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 69/7)
  - Legal File
    - Divorce papers (Box-folder 69/8)
    - Legal correspondence (Box-folder 69/9)
    - Traffic Court (Box-folder 69/10)
      - Affidavit
      - Auto registration documents
      - Correspondence
      - Traffic citations
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 69/11)
  - Medical File
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 69/12)
    - Prescriptions (Box-folder 69/13)
    - Printed matter
      - Brochures [health clinics] (Box-folder 69/14)
      - Dietary (Box-folder 69/15)
      - General health concerns
    - Receipts (Box-folder 69/16)
    - Statements
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box-folder 69/17)
    - Miscellany
  - Travel
    - Expenses [lodging, meals, transportation]
      - Domestic (Box-folder 70/1)
      - Foreign (Box-folder 70/2)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 70/3)
    - Printed Matter
      - Maps (Box-folder 70/4)
      - News Clips [foreign] (Box-folder 70/5)
      - Travel Brochures
        - Asia (Box-folder 70/6)
        - Europe (Box-folder 70/7)
        - South America (Box-folder 70/8)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 70/9)
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 70/10)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Jazz musicians' birthday calendars (1973 znd 1979) (Box-folder 70/11)
    - Miscellany [i.e. handwritten notes, tarot cards, lock of hair from Eric Mingus' first haircut] (Box-folder 70/12)
    - Cultivation of personal magnetism in seven progressive steps, by Edmund Shaftesbury. Meriden, Conn.: Ralston University Press, 1925. Pages were carved out the center of this book and it served as a housing for Mingus' firearm. (Box 71)
    - Addresses and telephone numbers [unsorted] (Box 72-73)
    - Business cards (Box 74)
    - Leather valise (Box 84)
Appendix A: Mingus Tune List by Reference Number
001 Alive and Living in Dukeland (#29)
002 Arts of Tatum and Freddie Webster
003 Better Get Hit In Your Soul
004 Bemoanable Lady
005 Boogie Stop Shuffle
006 Boogie Stop Shuffle
007 Carolyn "Keki" Mingus 2
008 Celia (#28) (missing)
009 Celia
010 Chair in the Sky
011 Dry Cleaner From Des Moines
012 Cumbia and Jazz Fusion
013 Diane (Alice's Wonderland)
014 Depressions
015 Dizzy Profile
016 Don't Be Afraid, the Clown's Afraid Too (#13)
017 Duke's Choice (#17)
018 Ecclusiastics (#3)
019 Eclipse (#10)
020 Eclipse
021 Da Oo-Ah Oo-Um Blues (missing)
022 Duke Ellington's Sound of Love
023 Please Don't Come Back from the Moon
024 Todeskalte
025 Epitaph (missing)
026 Extrasensory Perception (E.S.P.)
027 Fables of Faubus
028 Farwell Farewell
029 Farwell Fairwell
030 Frank Maybry, Jr.
031 Freedom (#27)
032 Good-bye Pork Pie Hat (#18)
033 Good-bye Pork Pie Hat
034 Good-bye Pork Pie Hat
035 Hobo-Ho
036 Hot Dogs for Lunch
037 I of Hurricane Sue
038 It's Nice of You to Come to My Funeral
039 Jelly Roll
040 Jive Five Floor Four
041 Jump Monk (#2)
042 Just for Laughs Saps
043 Little Royal Suite (#26)
044 Love's Fury
045 No. 1 Grandson (#16)
046 No. 2 (Rebop & Bebop)
047 Nouroog (#14)
048 The Man Who Never Sleeps
049 Meditation
050 Mingus' Lo Slo Bluze
051 Mingus Fingers (#7)
052 Harris + Mingus Fingers
053 Myself When I Am Real
054 New Foundland
055 Nobody Knows
056 Noddin' Ya Head Blues
057 Noddin' Ya Head Blues
058 No. 1
059 No. 3 (Opus 3)
060 Orange Was the Color of Her Dress
061 Peggy's Blue Skylight
062 Make Believe
063 Make Believe
064 Pilobolus
065 Portrait (#9)
066 Portrait (#9)
067 Portrait
068 Pithecanthropus Erectus
069 Prisoner of Love
070 Purple Heart
071 Reincarnation of a Lovebird (#22)
072 Reincarnation of a Lovebird
073 Revelations
074 Self-Portrait in Three Colors
075 Sketch #1
076 Sketch #3
077 Some are Sioux
078 Something Like A Bird
079 Sweet Sucker Dance
080 Shoes of the Fisherman's Wife
081 Shoes of the Fisherman's Wife
082 Slop
083 Good-bye Eric
084 Sue's Changes
085 Taurus At the Arena of Life - Pt. 1
086 Taurus At the Arena of Life - Pt. 2
087 Subdued Passion Epitaph
088 String Quartet
089 Three of Four Shades of Blue
090 Three Worlds of Drums
091 Thrice Upon a Theme
092 Touch My Beloved's Thought
093 Todo Modo
094 Way Down Blues
095 Way Down Blues
096 Wee
097 Ysabel's Table Dance
098 Weird Nightmare
099 Arts of Tatum and Freddie Webster
100 Better Get Hit In Your Soul
101 Good-bye Pork Pie Hat
102 Sweet Blues
103 Candy
104 Make Me Know It
105 Frankie and Johnnie
106 Touch
107 Percussion Discussion
108 B.F.T.
109 Miss Bliss
110 Miss Bliss
111 Fess Williams Soul
112 Hot Town
113 Enchantment
114 Diane
115 Mind-Readers Convention
116 Little Royal Suite
117 The Clown's Afraid Too
118 School Boy
119 Carolyn "Keki" Mingus 1
120 Half Mast Inhibition
121 Bus Voice
122 Nobody Knows
123 Devil Woman
124 Better Get Hit In Your Soul
125 Celia
126 Something Like A Bird
127 Swinging an Echo
128 Diane (incomplete)
129 Taurus At the Arena of Life
130 Big Jim Whitey's Mule
131 Black Saint and the Sinner Lady
132 Tea for Two
133 Wednesday Night Prayer Meeting
134 Freedom
135 Us Is Too
136 Jelly Roll
137 Our Last Kiss
138 But You
139 II Worlds of Drums
140 Portrait
141 Eclipse
142 I of Hurricane Sue
143 Don't Be Afraid, the Clown's Afraid Too
144 Dianeland - Adagio Ma Non Troppo
145 Dianeland (Myself When I Am Real)
146 Something Like A Bird
147 Herricane Sue [sic]
148 Nostalgia in Times Square (Strollin')
149 Nostalgia in Times Square (Strollin')
150 Cumbia and Jazz Fusion
151 Ecclusiastics
152 Better Get Hit In Your Soul
153 Better Get Hit In Your Soul (#6)
154 Haitian Fight Song (#23)
155 O.P.
156 E's Flat, Ah's Flat Too (#21)
157 Minor Intrusion
158 Arts of Art Tatum and Freddie Webster
159 Lush Life
160 Where Does A Man Go?
161 The Clown's Afraid Too
162 Taming of the Sioux
163 Once Upon A Time There Was A Holding Corp.
164 Don't Let It Happen Here
165 School Boy
166 Wednesday Night Prayer Meeting
167 Tom's Take Over
168 John Doe
169 Weird Nightmare
170 Eulogy for Rudy Williams
171 Unknown
172 Dark Lightings
173 Winds
174 12 Alder Place
175 Devil/Fascination
176 Haitian Fight Song
177 Half Mast Inhibition
178 Half Mast Inhibition
179 Half Mast Inhibition
180 Passions of A Woman Loved
181 Weird Nightmare
182 East Coasting
183 Paris In Blue
184 What Love
185 Atomic Bomb
186 Ssi-Cla-Cal
187 Critic String Quartet
188 No Where No
189 Baby Take A Chance With Me
190 Night and Day
191 I'll Never Smile Again
192 All the Things You Are
193 I Left My Heart In San Francisco
194 The Man I Love
195 Study in Lines
196 Memories of You
197 Stormy Weather
198 Laura
199 I Can't Get Started
200 Body and Soul
201 Gone With the Wind [?]
202 You Go to My Head
203 As Time Goes By
204 The Man Who Never Sleeps
205 Weird Nightmare
206 Sketch #2
207 Sketch #4 - 42nd St.
208 Portrait
209 Arts of Tatum and Freddie Webster
210 Alive and Living in Dukeland (#29)
211 Montage
212 Isabel's Table Dance
213 Isabel's Table Dance (Tijuana Table Dance)
214 Unknown
215 You're My Everything
216 Us Is Two (Too)
217 Sketch #5
218 Jelly Roll
219 Shadows - Themes
220 Boogie Stop Shuffle
221 Diane (Alice's Wonderland)
222 Hurricane Sue
223 Remember Rockefellar at Attica
224 Noddin' Ya Head Blues
225 Song with Orange
226 Sue's Changes
227 Blue Cee
228 Chord Progressions
229 Instrumental parts and melody lines
230 Melodies with chords - lead sheets
231 Score fragments
232 Unknown
233 Modern Jazz Writer
234 Intermit
235 Unknown
236 Nacirema
237 Sally Wanna Doodle All Day
238 Back A Few Years (Tijuana Table Dance)
239 Haitian Fight Song
240 Open Letter to Duke
241 Gunslinging Bird
242 Love Is A Dangerous Necessity
243 Blue Tide
244 Jack the Bear
245 Far Wells, Mill Valley
246 Pithecanthropus Erectus - Mingus Dance #1
247 O.P. - Mingus Dance #2
248 Myself When I Am Real - Mingus Dance #3
249 Dianeland - Adagio Ma Non Troppo
250 Freedom - Mingus Dance #4
251 Half Mast Inhibition - Mingus Damce #5
252 Dizzy Moods - Mingus Dance #6
253 Diane - Mingus Dance #7
254 Ysabel's Table Dance - Mingus Dance #8
255 Haitian Fight Song - Mingus Dance #9
256 Epitaph (Main score)
257 Epitaph (#2)
258 Epitaph (#3)
259 Epitaph (#4)
260 Epitaph (#5)
261 Epitaph (#6)
262 Epitaph (#7)
263 Epitaph (#8)
264 Epitaph (#9)
265 Epitaph (#10)
266 Epitaph (#11)
267 Epitaph (#12)
268 Epitaph (#13)
269 Epitaph (#14)
270 Epitaph (#15)
271 Epitaph (#16)
272 Epitaph (#17)
273 O.P.
274 The Chill of Death
275 Soul
276 Please Don't Come Back from the Moon
277 Freedom
278 Monk, Bunk and Vice Versa
279 Wolverine Blues
280 Hot Town
281 Unidentified
282 Subdued Passion
283 Nouroog
284 Make Me Know It
285 Fess Williams Soul
286 Epitaph
287 Please Don't Come Back from the Moon
288 Eclipse
289 Sketch #2 (Fly Away With Me)
290 Better Get Hit In Your Soul
291 Musical Style of Charles Mingus
292 Spiral Bound Manuscript
293 Remember Rockefellar at Attica (Just for Laughs Saps)
294 Sketches (1-6)
295 Lead Sheets - Blue Team Version
296 Lead Sheets - A,B,C
297 Lead Sheets - D,E,F
298 Lead Sheets - G,H,I
299 Lead Sheets - J,K,L
300 Lead Sheets - M,N,O
301 Lead Sheets - P,Q,R
302 Lead Sheets - S
303 Lead Sheets - T
304 Lead Sheets - U,V,W,X,Y,Z
Appendix B: Andrew Homzy Guide to the Music of Charles Mingus
The Andrew Homzy Guide to the Music of Charles Mingus is a descriptive catalog of Charles Mingus music manuscript compositions and arrangements compiled by Andrew Homzy and Francine Dupuis circa May 1984. Existing as a separate volume, the catalog outlines in detail each numbered manuscript on a one-page form, which includes composer, arranger, copyist, publisher, manuscript format (i.e. full score, condensed score, instrumental part, etc.), instrumentation, and other information available about the piece. These fact sheets, arranged chronologically by reference number, are bound separately and can be examined upon request. There are 304 number assignments.